Let's add a Hip Slide to our Choo Choo Shimmy.
So let's review the hip slide real quickly.
Feet are slightly apart.
Make sure your knees are just soft, bring your belly button in, lift your chest and these hips are going to slide just outside of your body line.
If you imagine keeping your head right in the center, the hips are going to slide on either side of that.
And then we're going to keep pressing them down so that they stay parallel to the floor as much as possible.
Good.
Now, let's get our choo choo shimmy going.
Up on relevee, pull those hips in toward the rib cage.
Now we're going to be shifting our weight during our choo choo shimmy and we're going to be using our hips and side muscles to press the hips side to side.
So side and side.
Keep your body in the center and let your hips go on either side of you.
Watch those ankles that they stay press in toward each other.
Where's your belly button?
Make sure its touching your spine.
Lift your chest, breath.
Make sure everything is in its right place.
And keep those hips moving nice and evenly.
You can do this best by practicing in the mirror.